Good is no fun at all.
The Bad Guys is a family, comedy, crime film directed by Pierre Perifel.
When the Bad Guys, a crew of criminal animals, are finally caught after
years of heists and being the world’s most-wanted villains, Mr.
Wolf brokers a deal to save them all from prison.
Wolf (voice), played by Sam Rockwell.
Snake (voice), played by Marc Maron.
Tarantula (voice), played by Awkwafina.
Shark (voice), played by Craig Robinson.
Piranha (voice), played by Anthony Ramos.
Professor Marmalade (voice), played by Richard Ayoade.
The Bad Guys is a 2022 American animated heist comedy film loosely based on The Bad Guys
children's book series by Aaron Blabey, and produced by DreamWorks Animation.
The film was directed by Pierre Perifel in his feature directorial debut, written by Etan Cohen, and stars the voices of Sam
Rockwell, Marc Maron, Awkwafina, Craig Robinson, Anthony Ramos, Richard Ayoade, Zazie Beetz, Alex Borstein, and Lilly Singh.
It tells the story of a criminal group of anthropomorphic animals who, upon being caught, pretend to attempt to reform
themselves as model citizens, only for their leader to find himself genuinely drawn to changing his ways for good.
Work on the film started in March 2018, with Cohen writing the screenplay.
The characters and themes drew inspiration from various crime films and anime series such as Pulp Fiction (1994), the Ocean's film trilogy, Lupin III, and
Sherlock Hound, while the inspiration for the film's animation style came from Sony Pictures Animation's Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse (2018).
Production began at DreamWorks Animation's Glendale campus, and some additional production assets were borrowed
from Jellyfish Pictures, with voice acting being done remotely due to the COVID-19 pandemic.
The Bad Guys was released theatrically by Universal Pictures in several
countries on March 16, 2022, and in the United States on April 22.
It received positive reviews from critics and grossed $250.8 million.
A sequel, The Bad Guys 2, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of based on novel or book,
snake, wolf, affectation, spider.
The tone is lighthearted.